so the other day I'm
my translation for oppa Donna and ten
onaconda the five assumed aggregates and
i wanted to use the word bridge for with
madonna the five bridge tickets so they
Luke would convey him the meaning of
what Madonna is anyway that connection
between let's say body and mind in
between the thing that connects them and
that that bridges an imagination oh well
I mean you can but if you translate it
like that you would have to explain it a
lot more I mean which other way we could
translate you put on it to explain
because obviously the petitioners views
are already well then it's kupatana that
makes them that makes inclusion
religions petunia because of his super
Donna because of his assumption because
of the his mental bridges so to speak so
you want to look at the what the nature
of OPA donna is and then find a word
they would that could possibly convey
that regardless of the view that's
reading it that doesn't mean everybody
will understand it but means that if
they were to understand it then they'll
see the point of that
translation straddling the bridge
necessarily would do that but it
certainly can enrich the description of
it like the five aggregates aggregates
for example that's a knowledge
translation we spoke one before condom
literally I think means heap strike hips
so five heaps I see five different
things heaped together they don't become
one thing they don't merge they don't
come together but with it with the
assumption in place yeah you sort of
your bridge you bridge them together
into this kind of morphed thing when you
think it's you know emo my feeling my
perception it's over coming out at the
same place my sense of self erection
and that's how you get this whole sense
of like directionality of the experience
me towards the world but if you actually
start seeing that's why when the Buddha
was doing the analysis he wasn't doing
the analysis for the sake of abstract
satisfaction of some theoretical
knowledge it was more like discerning that there
it was more like discerning that there
are actually three layers of your
experience in terms of action for
example or they're like three different
layers of feeling simultaneously as a
possibility present so it's not like I
feel this then I feel that it's just
these feelings there then this feeling
is there then this feeling is there a
pleasant feeling is independent of an
unpleasant feeling Pleasant and
unpleasant feeling are independent of
neither pleasure nor doesn't feel in
other way whatever phenomenon arises
arises in itself for itself so to speak
but you don't use that in order to
justify some as I said some theoretical
outlook how everything is just out there
not yours you use that to see the things
that are yours your sense of ownership
your sense of this is - five aggregates
of these feelings or these actions can
only be appropriated because they have a
reason on their own and you realize that
you get to realize their independence
from your sense of ownership by seeing
that it's theater it's five of them it's
two of them even if it's just one of
them because the man on the main
characteristics of a sense of self is
it's that kind of single unity unity
like my eye I take this and I endure
that single Center oh I feel like this I
feel like that but you stopped putting
emphasis on the present feeling then you
realize well I feel like this I feels
like this or feels like that because
that's that's what that that is which
feeling has a reason it determines how
the self feels and that's where the
Buddha meant so which one isn't like if
if you say my sense of self by my self
feels pleasure of myself which myself
feels only pleasant feeling
how can itself remain standing when
there is unpleasant feeling well myself
feels all the feelings like yeah but
it's those feelings that arise first
then yourself feels them so how can you
say that in yours how can it say they
belong to you so in terms of the
aggregates the division of like five
aggregates it's to see that there are
five heaps at the foundation of any
experience you might be going through
proper being five well five components
remain like means five components of a
unit but you don't want to be coming
from a kind of unit because that means
you can coming from a point of view of
sense itself which is that unit and
that's when people do investigate the
five aggregates as components of their
sense of self now you want to see that
these five random heaps are the
necessary basis for your sense of self
that's how a sense of self cannot remain
holding on to that's assumed completely
tutors assume self centralized position
as if I am the master of these five five
components for my experience this is
mine yeah this is my experience but if you
yeah this is my experience but if you
look at okay my experience you don't
deny that this experience is mine within
that you discern five simultaneously
present heaps and you realize if these
five heaps that cannot be four or three
or one it's always five means none of
them can take centralized position I
mean they can in the assumption and
that's what assumption is a gratuitous
sort of parasite upon the structure of
the five but when you realize that even
when you assume you can only assume
because five were given beforehand which
means they're independent of your
assumption which means they're
independent of the results of your
assumption which is the sense of self so
then you realize when the sense of self
is not yours this my experiences my
cannot be my cuz it's actually rooted in
these five random things that have a
reason on their own simultaneously
present you want to see there so you
want to see the faces of five within
that sense of ownership not after is an
afterthought or left right from it like
when you have a sense of ownership you
don't okay now I'm gonna go and find
these five things look
when I have the sense of ownership
within that I'm gonna discern these five
things or three things depending on your
pros two things the diet as the Buddha
would deal with this right now
you want to see that whatever has a
reason has a reason on its own you're
not its creator are not being its
creator your sense of ownership that's
undeniable for boo to Gina you have to
see the sense of ownership as second not
as first and that's how you you start to
undo the ownership when you see it as
redundant when you see it as not
fundamental because one doesn't see this
separate list of each you don't see the
separated nests of each other on the
right basis you see it in abstract
theory which is which left that sense of
ownership excluded from that theory so
that's I mean you want to be investing
it in the five aggregates but not on the
terms of your ownership but within the
basis necessary basis of that ownership
and that's nuts that's also what what
differentiates abstract thinking from
concrete thinking and reflection and
contemplation in terms of body speech -
exactly the three simultaneously present
domains independent of each other in any
living experience as a whole whether you
you are smart - dumb educated or not
three different domains there's always
three different domains like three
different layers it's what constitutes
just your sense of self directed a layer
of a physical a layer of verbal layer of
mental and they don't merge they don't
come into each other they don't they
don't sort of they don't cross from one
into the other there is nothing that
goes from mental domain can flows into
then and goes becomes part of the verbal
domain you have mental thought that then
results in breaking on a certain speech
in a verbal domain or results in a
breaking of a certain action in a
physical domain so like when people try
to
but the closest to the correlation you
can get is with this this is with this
type of thought this is the leaning of
the physical domain to lose that action
but there is nothing that bridges them
together except the assumption of the
bridge together except neo padana and
that's the point here done to realize
that when people try to investigate
things they usually end up looking for
correlation and often try to use the
Buddhist description of potential father
it's not incidental that empathise own
father becomes cause and effect so that
correlation of these two simultaneously
present things becomes their causation
literally oh it's when this happens then
this happens
yeah what this happens this can happen
or even this could happen but the point
is that there is no connection between
these two simultaneously present
phenomena that's why if you start
discerning this you start discerning the
principle of simultaneity which is what
Matisse and father is cuz yet with this
this is that is undeniable but that's
the closest that that correlation can
come but for an ignorant mind mind that
comes from the point of view assumption
that's invisible so for them this
becomes this so having intention to to
sit down and then there's the intention
in in the mind and then electrons or
whatever start firing up but exactly
although none of that can be object to a
perception which means you what is the
basis then you ask yourself what is the
basis for me having all these views that
or have this intention and then they the
electrons are firing and that's why my
arm is moving and doing this how can you
even know that except in this abstract
theory that you use to bridge that gap
between this invention this action
that's all you can say I am I'm doing
something because there is there is that
intention present in my mind and that's
what I mean and it like it might seem
almost like a minor thing but it's a
it's actually the most crucial one
that's why the good of this competition
but as the most fundamental principle
because if you discerned them if you are
able to discern the principle of two
simultaneous things present together
without assuming any relationship
between the two means there won't be any
conceiving between the two but he
conceives in apart from both neither
mine whatever he assumes relationship
with it which means ah you you get to
see them related which is order the form
of connection the slightest formal
relationship units a relationship of
denial I deny this I deny the existence
of this he totally formulation.if with
us as such it means it's already our
connection so in terms of the action you
have say you have a thought to eat
something and then you're actually eating it if
and then you're actually eating it if
the mind is affected by ignorance if the
mind has not developed sufficient basis
of necessary amount of mindfulness of
the spirit you will think it's the same
thing and that's all their form of
identity identity between the thought
and the physical action and whenever
there is any shape of of assumed
identity means your sense of self is
there to that extent to that extent
you're appropriating it just through the
extent of lack of clarity you don't
necessarily have to think explicitly
this is my this is my action this is my
food I am eating I am eating no it's
enough to think that your thought of
eating food and physical eating food are
the same thing oh then you start
thinking oh no these are completely
different things as in two separate
identities either way you either
overshoot or undershoot amok
you you you are unable to see them to
the extent the reason they that they are
arisen you Rene you are unable to see
them that with the present enduring
thought of eating food there is the
physical eating food so the separate
domains so when these things arise it
will be it will require develop
mindfulness - not given rise to that natural
- not given rise to that natural
confusion and conflating of the two
domains as in thought of food means this
food and that's the nature of that's how
people are connected so to speak with
their sensuality potential cravings
because sensuality can never step
outside of the physical domain yet it's
fully governed by the mental assumption
of sensuality because it's not in
physical sensuality it's not contained
in physical objects of the senses it's
contained in you assuming the connection
between the two which then thought of
something pleasurable engagement with my
body with that pleasurable is that
pursuit of that thought so it's the
directional assumption that takes me
from I want this to I want to talk about
it - I want to have it physically
failing to see that wanting it on your
mind in your mind verbally talking about
it on level of speech physically
pursuing it a three separate domains
that can never come together or when
you're going for the pleasure when all
you see
well that's the thing sensuality assumes
that end result which end result is
merging of it all that's why the whole
notion of trying to satisfy your desire
like set this idea of satisfaction is a
hybrid of these three domains it's a
view but that's what I mean that's the
trash that's we put agenda start with
for some reason free from sexuality
that's what they start with that hybrid
is their first point so it's all about
finding the way out of it it's about
undoing it and you undo where you see
that your hybrid of the view of
satisfying your desires it's actually
simultaneously formed determined by the
three independent separate domains that
are always simultaneously present and
that's why they're so hard to discern
it's not like one then the two comes
then you get to see one fully no it's
always three and they're always
simultaneously present you can attend
them differently you can't see them all
at once sweet yeah domain of body domain
a speech domain of the mind but the
desire is the assumption
the end goal of that whole of that whole
sort of directional connection of my
thought my speech my action my
satisfaction but even people who like
people who are not a free from
sensuality people are not free from
wrong view even they know that there is
a problem with that hybrid which is
sensuality let's ensure it is because
they like even the more even the person
who is the most Bentham on on central
pursuits still knows deep down inside
that you can't really satisfy your
desires because your desire is on your
desires on the mental level is somewhere
else yet the only means of comprehending
any form of satisfaction would be on a
physical level if you give if you if you
accept desire in the face value in the
mental level then you you leave yourself
no other option than to try to set
further on a physical level but it's not
the same thing it's completely different
thing so that's why it sensuality
requires ignorance it requires a blind
eye applied to this very nature that
actually these are two separate things
and physically scratching itch and even
getting the satisfaction from scratching
requires you to not look closely and see
that yeah that's one thing but my mental
desire projection towards the end game
of sensuality is a completely thing and
it's still there so then you need that
belief of sensuality whereby when
physically scratching becomes unpleasant
that's when you feel satisfied but the
thought of you wanting that satisfaction
hasn't changed you only forgot about it
at the time so if your whole point of
central pursuit of central projection is
to get rid of the pressure of the desire
on the mental level why not address it
right there stop bothering with physical
pursuit which is clearly like like like
sidestepping taking away all the
different domain can have no influence
on the mental domain Inlet says domain
is craving so you go to another term
exactly try and sort it out to try it
aloud the crane must but the only reason
you can stay engaged in that other
domain is if the craving remains present
on the mental domain
I mean so it even contradicts that very
attempt like in order to go to another
domain you need the presence of craving
in a mental domain but you go there to
try to get rid of the craving in the
mental domain so that's why the physical
restraint is not optional has to come
first always because it's a complete
mess up location so you just have to
stop doing it in order to see where the
problem really is so she's on the mental
domain so you see the desire you see
that you see those two domains yeah you
see the desire and then you see the
pressure but even that pressure towards
physical action or verbal action output
you realize oh well even that pressure
is still in the mental level the only
way that physical or verbal will be
manifested is if I act out of it that's
the only shape or form that this can
manifest in other words you can have all
the desire you want in your mind
pressuring you to do something
physically unless you're actively
deciding to do something physically
there is nothing manifest in your
physical domain on account of that
design because you haven't done anything
there is nothing manifested in a verbal
domain on a kind of a mental desire to
say something because you haven't said
it and you guys oh that's all I have to
do in order to protect these two domains
and when you do that then that assumed
well that pressure that comes out of
that assumption because again as I said
it's about undoing that hybrid
assumption and until that's undone there
going to be a degree of pressure towards
physical or towards verbal domain coming
from your mental craving but the more
you do it the less pressure there is the
less pressure there is the cleaner the
nature it becomes oh there is a thought
of this there was you used to be
governed by the promise of pleasure in
the physical domain but even that
promise of pleasure was fully mental can
never be really the physical pleasure
because the only way to have physical
pleasure is to physically have pleasure
but when you have a desire mental desire
to it's physical pressure that's that's
a physical actions your mental desire
for physical pleasure means there is no
actual physical pleasure but we act as
if that mental desire
physical question is on the physical
level so all I need to do is extend my
arm and take and touch what I want to
have so it reminds me of this like if I
get frustrated if someone does something
to me and they in my mind I'm angry I'm
frustrated and so I don't shout i
restrain myself but then this is view I
must get out the anger summer I must get
out the frustration because keeping it
in my mind is going to give me cancer so
me so I must get it out somehow by
saying my ran Singh but by telling
someone else yeah that's mean but your
your anger doesn't come out of your mind
I must get out because the pressure did
well you mistake that pressure that was
revealed by your restraint you must take
it to be caused by your restraint
so a person who restrains their anger
physically and verbally has revealed the
pressure of the mental frustration they
wanted to express itself Frank really
yeah reveals it but people would think
that oh this pressure wasn't there as in
I wasn't aware of it before cuz before
whenever I thought something I would say
something whenever I thought something I
would do something but now I stopped
doing it stop saying it and now I have
all this pressure that are not giving
into and then they think that that
pressure has been caused by not giving
into but it hasn't that if that pressure
were not there regardless of your
restraint or not you wouldn't have never
acted out of anger mental anger would
never make you do something physically
or say something verbal yet that's how
you use to act so now when you study
restraint in that action you realize
that oh the pressure that I became aware
of it now has been revealed by my
restraint as something that was always
there not caused by my restraint as
something that wasn't there before and
when that view changes that's when you
start valuing the restraint for as long
as you don't change that view you will
blame restraint for the pressure that
God revealed you think pressure got
created I better release it cuz I will
implode
but that's what I mean you only need to
you don't need to look further than just
to see how were you behaving when you
don't need to restrain yourself you
realize they still that pressure day you
just don't feel it cuz you get to turn a
blind eye to it could you get to act
physically and verbally because there is
no restraint so you see that so you
don't there is a pressure build-up
quickly release there is a pressure
build-up are one release if pressure
builds up cuz you restrain you saw the
pressure that's been building up but
whether you destroy or not pressure will
be building up and if you take pressures
to be the problem
you realize restraint is not an option
you must be done because how can I deal
with the pressure if I keep releasing it
right away
every second soon as you start building
up a quickly quickly open everything but
you're trying to deal with the business
with the rising of the pressure so the
only way to deal with the rising of the
pressure is to let the pressure arise
and not leak it out let it be exactly
let it be then you get to see where
pressure has come from but oh is it off
pressure is gone I have to wait for new
pressure to come to see where it's
coming from but if you keep letting the
pressure out how can you see where it's
built where it's being built up from
first thing the pressure builds up
builds up builds up and once and then
exactly it cannot no amount of pressure
builders can make you act in a different
domain mental pressure is mental
pressure that's that's why always the
responsibility for direction never
changes even if a person is sort of
losing their mind so to speak
fundamentally if they choose to act
physically or verbally that's on them so
no amount of mental pressure buildup can
make your hands legs head do things you
choose that pressure to be the reason
for you asses that's why inherently
, as a form of action is based on
ignorance it's based on that assumption
based on that bridge between the domains
that are unreachable
when you fully discern that
his domains can never connect you
realize oh there is no professional
Norman or mentor what used to cause
pressure mentally such as prospect of
death or prospect of of some well some
significant experience
you realize even that pressure that were
being built up in your mind was because
there were traces of assumption of
connection pressure build up in the mind
means there is a possibility of acting
out of it
on the physical or verbal domain you
remove the possibility I acted out
acting out of it as in you remove the
assumptions of of the slightest
connection between these domains there
is no pressure to arise even if the
highway robbers are chopping you limb by
limb to summer cold calls me night yeah
calls me something say something
threaten me or whatever says I'm an
idiot and that they wrote that domain
but then I get angry in my mind because
of an external speech yeah it's it's
it's it's the anger that has a reason
remain fully enclosed on a mental level
but you didn't know how to deal with it
so then you jumped on a verbal level or
a physical level but if you know how to
not be affected by that prospect of
arising anger on the mental level why
would you be looking to express it
anywhere else there will be nothing to
express but for as long as you give in
to a form of expressing anger through
physical or verbal domains means to that
extent you're maintaining belief that
anger is expressible those domains which
means how can you then uprooted where
anger rest have you mind releasing the
pressure keep believing that the
releasing the pressure in completely
unconnected domains is the way of
dealing with pressure so locked revenge
like Oh killing someone yeah exactly who
that's the ultimate sort of that's
extension of this perverted principle
but then again you realize that if there
is a pressure on the level of the mind
yeah there is an assumption of the level
of the mind that results in this
pressure which is uncomfortable but you
realize the only way to really deal with
it is to treat it on the level of the
mind to overcome it and that's what we
were meant when he said even if a person
lives physically withdrawn from
sensuality unless his mind has been
withdrawn from assuming the same he's
still wet in the same sense you take the
two sticks out of the water but you
still won't be able to light the fire
with them because they're still wet so
having been withdrawn physically then
now you need to dry out your mind from
those same assumptions they kept making
your head physically and you can use any
form of pressure any form of that mental
discomfort you can use it as a symptom
of some humidity left so to speak and
when there is no pressure means the
sticks are completely dry and then you
it will be self-evident so so where
there once was pressure so yes you -
your measurement there yeah when you no
longer there's no longer that pressure
to act exactly that is a sign that you
are not misconceiving
the nature of the three domains so that
is a sign that you are not as deluded as
you were before so you say your there is
anger well seeing that like anger
requires a degree of that pressure on
the mental level is discomfort that's
why that's why like the right view
doesn't automatically jump into freedom
from sensuality and anger like that's
what is that the step of sakagami in
between weakening of these things
weakening of these assumptions there's
not much of a pressure exactly so for
somebody with the right view in
is virtually unable we'll be virtually
unable to act the same extent out of
anger or lust as somebody who doesn't
have the right view so for sakagami
he'll be even less able to act out of
these things but still to some extent
and anon Yamagami cannot really act or
say anything sensual and that's how he
approved it sensuality but on the mental
level there are still traces of certain
lacks of clarity in regard to certain
much more refined prevailed perversions
of the natural principles and that's
where the other hand she gets developed
if you approve that so having an angry
thought for Saudi Bona he might be
emotionally even affected but not to the
extent of going and just just killing
another hunt harming people in that in
that sense of like that full-on blind
rage which requires the sufficient
amount of that belief in connecting
these domains of mental and physical
output such chuckling um even less like
maybe on some extremely extremely
careless days too much sort of going on
mindfulness lapse for a long time he
might do things out of sensuality anger
but obviously that's like minuscule in
comparison to and then on ago he became
unable no amount of pressure no amount
of adverse circumstances no matter of
loss of mindfulness can make these
domains connect through assumption again
because he dwelt on it long enough that
it became so clear that that's undoable
now you can't undo the Clara sisters
because those do mean we're truly
uncollectible to begin with that's why
the Buddha said it's because the mind
cannot really be polluted with these
things that's a liberation from
pollution of these things is possible so
when there's a unpleasant feeling
whatever is happening say somebody's
someone just stole something from you
you realize you this was stolen is an
unpleasant feeling that doesn't result
in anger or fear sure he is just a
disagreeable feeling that's it and
there's on a physical level as we spoke
about now buzz the aggregates of the
three types erection can say the same
for feeling and for perception that's
what writing that as a feeling feels
perception as soon as I see this
intention intense in a way yes oh you're
a recent feeling requires an assumption
for you to be acting towards or against
perceptions because feeling is felt
perception is perceived it's not that
you perceive what you feel like you what
you're perceiving is what you are
feeling so then you're dealing with what
you're perceiving that's how you deal
with what you don't know you can't
release your feelings and you can't
release the feeling out of the main of
feeling into the domain of perception
that's what would have said when the
asking what is feeling says feeling is
that which feels those perceptions that
which perceives perception perceives
feeling feels matter matters
consciousness cognizes intentions
intense whatever you want to translate
five heaps it's five heaps not like five
things did merge into one thing so no
amount of the expanse of the heap it's
still gonna be five heaps so when when
when is like five say five layers of
different things and then you have
another five layers of the same kind of
things just double it up so you say you
have a you have a towel you have a stone
you have a bucket you have a piece of
wood and a piece of metal then you have
another towel another pocket another
wood another minute then you have six
hours and 15 buckets and it and peep it
and heap it and he still if you go in
you'll see towel towel towel towel other
no matter towels it's still gonna be oh
these are all heap of towels what are
the domain of towels within the heap of
these different things a domain of
pieces of wood as in domain of wood I
don't my elbow washing my bucket no exactly so
my elbow washing my bucket no exactly so
no matter doesn't matter how expensive
the heap might become it's still gonna
be heap of five domains five natures
five types of things and that's what I
would have said doesn't matter well like
at the forum there's a matter if it's a
past form future form present form
personal impersonal internal external
big or small far or near up or down
he knows form is there doesn't matter
it's a blue tower red towel yellow towel
big Tower my tower so does towel towels
are there but you don't do this for the
sake of some kind of exercise in your
perception because obviously you can do
that in the similar I gave as a heap of
things that you can perceive but imagine
how hard becomes when it's your
experience its heaped like that but you
can only perceive the perceptions you
can't go and perceive in the same manner
feeling and method in other things
that's when Buddha said matter matters
feeling feels perception perceives and
so on consciousness cognisance that's
why Co so consciousness doesn't in
cognizing doesn't go in cognize matter
consciousness cognizes that's it that's
the extent of its of its heap so it's
the five heaps and you realize by having
five heaps completely independent
completely different completely unaware
of each other
heap of powers is unaware of the heap of
wood the heap of feelings is unaware of
the heap of perception it's the file
heaps that is the starting that is the
necessary - the connection you assume
the connections usually like
directionality of your ignorance with
the grain so I've had this feeling and
I'm perceiving this ah so I am feeling
this what I'm perceiving and it becomes
one thing becomes me and everything else
so you see doesn't matter if it's me
others me and others internal external
internal and external past future
present what matters is whichever way it
is of
particular things I've just described
that's already within the nature of the
five aggregates so by seeing that no like whatever
like whatever
whatever feels close to you what else
feels most personal to you whatever
feels most emotional significant to you
do realize it's it could have only
arisen and the basis of these five
random heaps they have no control over
because if there were nobody
if there are no domain of feelings to be
felt if the domain of perception is not
working if the main of consciousness is
not cognizing if the main intentions
cannot intend how could you be engaged
with anything in any shape or form how
could you be alive to begin so then you
realize that no matter what emotion
significance of what experience you
might be dealing with or trying to deal
with utilize it secondary to the basis
of the structure they have no saying and
that's how you lose concern you don't
lose concern in your in your ownership
in things they define you in in in
emotional attitudes by denying them you
lose concern by approaching them by
saying that they're rooted in something
that you cannot even you cannot even
slide this you cannot even have a
slightest conceiving of it as as having
a say in it you cannot even control it
to a slightest degree and that's why
this realization can very very often be
frightening for somebody who still not
letting go of that assume the ownership
of the of the experience of the whole of
me my world and my environment and
that's why as I said it's a mistake but
it's a good shooters mistake that is the
Buddha said it has no first point of
manifestation it's not like I wasn't
ignorant then I became ignorant no that
is the starting point and that's why
then people would just keep expanding on
it keep proliferating it further so you
already made the same mistake by
assuming this experience as a whole to
be use you assume that you have a saying
you assume that you have a say in the
domain of feeling the domain of
perception the domain of form the domain
of cognizer and because you took that
for granted then you just extend the
principle further so now from from this
fundamental domain i also assume i have
a domain in in I have either
I have a say in the domain of things
that I perceived to be mine that I've
acquired if you acquired something it
clearly wasn't yours beforehand the only
reason you could acquire it is because
it wasn't used beforehand if you were
truly yours if you were truly master
control of the owner
there will be no acquiring necessary so
acquiring is always a good sure it is
appropriation when I say acquiring I
don't mean you take this and put it next
to you because it's useful no I mean
sense of emotional ownership and you
will know whether you have that
emotional ownership whereby if you just
all you have to do is think about if
something comes and steals it is the
example you gave will you be emotionally
affected by it
why to what extent or if it changes if
you changes if you lose it if it stops
functioning I feel great I feel great
exactly great and then so if you never
forget that means you you never really
assumed you on the shape of things and
you can use all you want you won't be
blinded by it but that takes undoing and
like people can do that even further I
mean there is no end to how far you can
proliferate this to the point where
somebody said something to somebody else
somewhere else and I'm emotionally
affected because of that and that's one
thing that I took for granted now I
won't emotionally act out of it and make
sure that that person was unaware of my
existence had nothing to do with me
suffers on econo but he said to somebody
else somewhere else that upset me on a
completely different continent and as I
said it's just a proliferation of the
same the most fundamentally essential
principle turning a blind eye to the
basic truth that your experience as a
whole is not your own and that's why you
need to keep maintaining your sense of
ownership in regard to it because it
isn't yours and that's truly body public
recognition of impermanence is means
recognition of impossibility to own
because if you were the owner things
would last as long as you would want
them to last not as long they will want
to last now we're trying to hold things
together yeah it requires maintenance
that's what they do pradhana is holding
it also be good you know yeah to get
holding but I prefer the word assumption
for it because that's holding implies
you know what you hoped or you might
like ho-ho I better drop this that
assumption is much much less intentional
yet it's something you feel responsible
for an assumption literally means to
take things for granted to take things
at face value or experience the reason
must be mind cuz I'm the only one here
so I am the owner of this experience you
just gratuitously assume that and that's
why assumption is irreversible if you
undo it but you can only assume
something if you don't know what that
thing truly is because once you do know
what that thing truly is assumption is
cancelled he becomes redundant so if you
know that this thing cannot be mine no
matter you saying to you this is mine
and trying to rekindle the assumption of
this is mine can take place because now
you fully know that all these attitudes
are released in response to things not
being able to be mine in the first place
so you can only take something for
granted until you know what that thing
is that's why visa cancels our Vijay
Vijay is irreversible
once our hand becomes our and he cannot
undo the state of our we'll go
back to being a future if possible
so even if you were taking things
rightly so to speak the fact that you
were taking them at face value that's
already what assumption is so you can
have right assumptions sure but because
it's still an assumption to that extent
it's a wrong thing it's a wrong view to
that extent it's a perversion it's sort
of distortion of the right order so you
had the right idea yeah yeah that's all
you replace the wrong assumptions with
right assumptions you replace the the
wrong views with a with a locker with a
right view in the terms of you replace
the worldly views with a right world
view which is still fundamentally the
wrong view but then on account of the
right worldly view you get the right
right and it comes clear so you know our
assumption that there must not assume
anything but that's already within your
assumption what assumptions are you have
to find the right except for firstly for
petitioner its right to assume that he
must restrain himself physically
verbally in order to get to deal with
problems on the level of mind it's right
thing to assume the liberation is
possible because if it were impossible
you wouldn't even have the slightest
notion towards any sense of freedom but
the failure you do have a sense of like
notion of a sense of freedom from the
desire Center freedom from suffering
yeah you don't know if it's possible but
you assume that it's possible okay to
that extent it's an a right assumption
that can eventually result in undoing
all the assumption that's why we lament
craving is to be undone by the means of
craving it's the same principle in
regard to the topic of craving
but what will never result in undoing
craving is if you never start
understanding the nature craving if you
never start what will never result in on
doing the assumption is if you never
start to discern the nature of present
assumption if you just divide it into
wrong assumptions and right assumptions
this is wrong craving this is right
craving and that's it that's as far as
your work went which means you just
replaced bad with good but you're
equally bound by it you're equally bound
by karma by the distortion of the notion
of action by the distortion of the
notion that you are acting and for that
you need to go beyond good as well
beyond good cravings beyond good OPA
donnas beyond restraint in a way that's
why our hunt is beyond training there is
nothing for him to train anymore to say
no to to restrain no he's beyond it it's
inconceivable to do even that but
because it's irreversible he can't do
anything unwholesome I because there was
abandon way before he even abandoned
good that we would say like his behavior
has been purified beforehand when
purified behavior when right assumptions
when right types of craving become your
mode of being means you have replaced
the bad model being and now on account
of the right mode of being you get to
discern the further the nature of of
that distortion of those tools those
fundamental existential assumptions and
by undoing it then you go beyond good
action as well hence our and is beyond ,
of any kind good bad or neutral because
he's beyond he has undone old any any
distortion that there was